purevision.com 2014-07-03

# Privacy Policy : Bausch + Lomb

Effective Date: October 20, 2010

This Web Site is controlled by Bausch & Lomb Incorporated or its affiliates and operations (“ **Bausch + Lomb** ”). This Privacy Policy (the “ **Privacy Policy** ”) describes how we collect, use, transfer and disclose personally identifiable information (“ **Personal Information** ”) and certain statistical information that we may obtain about you through this Web Site or by other means. This Web Site may be hosted on servers located in the United States. If you are located in a non-US jurisdiction, please note that you may be transferring your Personal Information to the United States, a jurisdiction that may not provide an equivalent level of data protection to the laws in your home country. By using this Web Site or submitting any Personal Information to us, you acknowledge that you have read, understood and agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy.

##  Collection of Personal Information 

You can visit this Web Site without revealing any information about yourself. Our Web Site is not set up to track, collect, or distribute Personal Information about you (such as name, address, email address, telephone number and product preferences) unless you voluntarily input this information, such as during a registration or ordering process.

Our Web servers may automatically record statistical data about visitors to our Web Site (through the use of cookies and other means) for use in our analysis of the performance of our website. We may record the time, date, duration, and URL of the requests, along with information on the geographic location of visitors and technology used to gain access. These statistics are not used to personally identify you, but help us to understand how visitors are interacting with our Web Site. These statistics contain no Personal Information and are only used by our technical support staff and marketing teams for purposes of Web Site administration. You have the option to configure your Internet browser to notify you when you have received a cookie and to provide you with the choice to accept or decline to accept the cookie. Further, you have the option to block all cookies. To modify your browser settings click on the help section of your Internet browser and follow the instructions.

Any information you provide through this Web Site or by other means will be used by us only as described in the “How We Use Information” section of this Privacy Policy. We collect any Personal Information that you voluntarily provide including, where applicable, your name, contact information (phone number, email address and address), date of birth, job title, friend and family member names and contact information, hobbies, areas of interest, professional affiliations, brand and product preferences, source of referrals, products ordered and values, tax/VAT rate/ registration number, prescription data, credit card or bank account information, payment/billing terms, Bausch + Lomb credit limit and status, ship to address, bill to address, export terms, license information, and employer/business principal name and contract details. To the extent you provide Personal Information about friends and family members, you agree to provide such individuals with this Privacy Policy and to obtain their consent to provide the Personal Information.

##  How We Use Information 

The Personal Information we collect is used by us for internal purposes such as improving our products, for the purpose of fulfilling customer orders and promotional registrations, responding to customer inquiries, tracking payment of customer orders, managing customer accounts, learning about our customers’ needs and contacting customers for research and informational purposes. We also use the Personal Information for market research and marketing and promotional activities including direct marketing via email and postal mail, and for general business administration and management. You may opt-out of receiving email messages at any time by clicking an “unsubscribe” link contained in any promotional or other emails that we send to you. We will not share your Personal Information with other organizations except as set forth in this Privacy Policy. Unless otherwise required by law or if pertinent to a judicial or governmental investigation, it is not shared with other organizations or persons, except for third party service providers assisting us in collecting, assembling or processing this information as further described below. 

##  Third Party Service Providers 

We engage third parties to perform services in connection with the operation of this Web Site and our company. Examples of these services may include web site hosting, the provision of technology related services, payment processing and authorization, and promotional material distribution. We provide Personal Information to these third parties, but we authorize them to use this Personal Information only in connection with the services they perform on our behalf. In addition, such parties are bound by contract to establish reasonable measures to protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure.

We may also disclose your Personal Information in connection with a corporate restructuring, sale or assignment of assets, merger, or divestiture of Bausch & Lomb or any of our subsidiaries or affiliated companies. Personal Information may also be disclosed to protect our rights or property, to enforce our terms of use and legal notices or at the request of government regulators or other law enforcement officials and the courts (including the issuance of a valid subpoena), or otherwise as required or permitted by law. In these cases, we shall have no duty to notify you.

We will not use or share your Personal Information in ways unrelated to those described in this Privacy Policy without first notifying you and offering you a choice as to whether or not we may use your Personal Information in this different manner. 

##  Data Security 

We maintain reasonable technical, physical and organizational measures to protect Personal Information against accidental or unlawful destruction or accidental loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access. Unfortunately, no information security system can be 100% secure. As a result, although we strive to protect your Personal Information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of the Personal Information against any possible loss or unauthorized access.

##  Access to Your Information 

We provide users of this Web Site with reasonable access to the Personal Information maintained about them. Subject to any applicable legal requirements, you are given a reasonable opportunity to correct, amend, or delete your Personal Information that is inaccurate. In most circumstances you may do so by contacting us as described at the end of this Privacy Policy.

##  Data Integrity 

We take reasonable steps to ensure that the Personal Information we collect is relevant for the purposes for which it is to be used and that the Personal Information is reliable for its intended use and is accurate, complete and current. However, we must rely on individual users to provide and maintain accurate Personal Information. You are responsible for contacting us as described at the end of this Privacy Policy to update or correct your Personal Information whenever necessary.

##  Retention of Personal Information 

We will only retain Personal Information for as long as we are required to do so by applicable law(s), or for as long as necessary for the purpose(s) for which it is processed. We will delete Personal Information when it is no longer needed and, in any case, upon expiration of the maximum storage term set forth by applicable law.

##  Changes to This Privacy Policy 

If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will post a revised link on the home page of the Web Site that indicates “Revised Privacy Policy” or a comparable notification about the changes. You should check this Web Site periodically to see if any recent changes to this Privacy Policy have been made. You can also tell if this Privacy Policy has changed recently by reviewing the Effective Date posted at the beginning of this Privacy Policy.

##  Links to Other Internet Web Sites 

The privacy practices set forth in this Privacy Policy are for this Web Site and other specified activities only. Other sites hosted by third parties may have different practices. If you link to or otherwise visit any other websites managed by third parties, please review the privacy policies posted at those sites. We have no control over those websites and are not responsible or liable for the policies and practices followed by third parties.

##  How We Protect the Privacy of Job Applicants 

Personal information collected from job applicants is protected by Bausch & Lomb's “Protecting Applicant Privacy(68 KB, PDF)” policy.

##  US - EU Safe Harbor Participation 

Bausch + Lomb recognizes that the European Union (“EU”) has an “ominbus” data protection regime established pursuant to the European Data Protection Directive (95/46/EC) and that Switzerland has adopted a data protection law (together, “Data Privacy Laws”). Among other things, the Data Privacy Laws generally require “adequate protection” for the transfer of personally identifiable information about Bausch + Lomb customers in the EU and Switzerland ("European Customer Data") to Bausch + Lomb operations in the United States. Bausch + Lomb accordingly adheres to the requirements of the US/EU and US/Swiss Safe Harbor Privacy Principles published by the US Department of Commerce ("Safe Harbor") with respect to certain European Customer Data received in the United States from our affiliated companies in the EU and Switzerland. European Customer Data is handled in accordance with the descriptions of the handling of Personal Information in this Privacy Policy. In addition, Bausch & Lomb Incorporated’s Safe Harbor certification is intended to cover the offline collection of European Customer Data relating to details of sales calls, call notes, customer service, practitioner data, customer category, services agreements and related payments, clinical trial participation and recalls of products. For more information about Safe Harbor please refer to the US Department of Commerce website at http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/. Any individual in the EU or Switzerland who cannot resolve his or her issue directly with Bausch + Lomb can contact the local data protection authority for further information and assistance. Bausch + Lomb provides its EU and Swiss employees with more detailed information about its data handling practices through internal company policies.

##  Contact Us 

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, our privacy practices or our Safe Harbor participation, please contact:

Office of the Chief Privacy Officer  
Bausch & Lomb Incorporated  
One Bausch & Lomb Place  
Rochester, NY 14604-2701  
ph: (800) 782-5812  
email: [dataprivacy@bausch.com](mailto:dataprivacy@bausch.com)
